发生什么了
What's happened?
时间漩涡 不见了
The time vortex. It's gone.
我们着陆了 总得在某个地方吧
Well, we've landed. We've got to be somewhere.
这是个平行世界 对吧
It's parallel, right?
有着齐柏林飞艇的平行世界
Like a parallel Earth only they've got zeppelins?
我说的没错吧
Am I right? I'm right, aren't I?
一个我爸爸还活着的平行世界
A parallel world where my dad's still alive.
洛斯 他不是你爸爸
DOCTOR: Rose, he's not your father
她也不是你妈妈
and she is not your mother.
那是什么
What's that?
米奇 我们有能源了
Mickey, we've got power!
你是个精明的商人 约翰
You're a fine businessman, John.
但你不是上帝
But you're not God.
我在那儿做什么
What am I doing there?
但他并不仅看起来像我
He doesn't just look like me.
而是完全一样
He is exactly the same.
他们是什么
ROSE: What are they?
赛博人
Cybermen.
快走
Come on!
没有必要杀死我们
There's no need to damage us.
我们是很好的材料
We're good stock.
我们志愿进行升级
We volunteer for the upgrade programme.
把我们带去加工吧
Take us to be processed.
你含有叛逆成分
You are rogue elements.
但我们已经投降了
But we surrender.
你们不兼容
You are incompatible.
但我们在投降啊
But this is a surrender!
你们会被删除
You will be deleted.
听我说 我们投降了
But we're surrendering! Listen to me! We surrender!
你们是低等的
You are inferior.
人类将重生为赛博人
Man will be reborn as Cyberman
而你们会被彻底毁灭
but you will perish under maximum deletion.
删除 删除 删除
Delete. Delete. Delete.
那究竟是什么东西
What the hell was that?
先别管了 逃命要紧
Or how about instead, run!
所有人上车
Everybody in!
我要回去 我妻子还在里面
I've got to go back. My wife's in there.
那房子里的所有人都死了
Anyone inside that house is dead.
如果你想帮忙 就别让她白白死去
If you want to help, then don't let her die for nothing.
马上和我们一起走
You've got to come with us right now.
快上车 赶快啊
Come on, get a move on.
洛斯 她不是你妈妈
Rose, she's not your mother.
我知道
I know.
赶快
Come on.
聊够了
Finished chatting?
我从没见过这么慢的逃亡
Never seen a slower getaway in my life!
那是什么东西
What was that thing?
我家乡的一点科技
Little bit of technology from my home.
没有光了 耗尽了吗
It's stopped glowing. Has it run out?
它正处于能量循环阶段
It's on a revitalising loop.
大概四小时后就会恢复
It'll charge back up in about four hours.
那么我们手无寸铁了
Well, so we don't have a weapon anymore.
我们有拳头
Yeah, we've got weapons.
对付不了金属人
Might not work on those metal things,
但对付他那样的人绰绰有余
but they're good enough for men like him.
离他远点 他做错什么了
Leave him alone! What's he done wrong?
你知道的 他设陷阱搞垮了政府
Oh, you know, just laid a trap that's wiped out the government
使得卢密克掌握了大权
and left Lumic in charge.
如果我是他们的人
If I was part of all that,
你认为我会把妻子留在房子里吗
do you think I'd leave my wife inside?
也许你的计划出错了
Maybe your plan went wrong.
但我们仍有理由处决你
Still gives us the right to execute you, though.
说到处决 你们这是在逼我成为敌人
Talk about executions, you'll make me your enemy.
给你们一个很好的建议 你们不会想这样的
And take some really good advice, you don't want to do that.
没差别
All the same,
我们有证据证明
we have evidence that says
皮特·泰勒从20.5年开始为卢密克工作
Pete Tyler's been working for the Lumic since 20.5.
真的吗
Is that true?
告诉他们 穆尔女士
Tell them, Mrs M.
我们有一个政府间谍为我们提供消息
We've got a government mole who feeds us information.
卢密克的私人文件 他的南美业务等等
Lumic's private files, his South American operations, the lot.
一周两次进行秘密无线电传送
Secret broadcasts twice a week.
传送自"双子星"
Broadcasts from Gemini?
你怎么知道
And how do you know that?
我就是双子星 那就是我
I'm Gemini! That's me!
你当然会这么说
RICKY: Yeah, well, you would say that.
无线电加密波长657 九位二进制
Encrypted wavelength 657, using binary 9.
我为卢密克工作的唯一原因
That's the only reason I was working for Lumic,
就是收集信息
to get information.
我还以为广播是发给安全中心的 结果得到什么
I thought I was broadcasting to the security services. What do I get?
一帮史酷比团伙
Scooby Doo and his gang.
竟然还用货车
They've even got the van.
不不 传教士知道自己在做什么
No, no, but the Preachers know what they're doing.
里奇说他是伦敦的头号通缉犯
Ricky said he's London's most wanted.
呃 那不是确切的说法
Yeah, that's not exactly...
什么不确切
Not exactly what?
我是伦敦的头号违规停车犯
I'm London's most wanted for parking tickets.
这下好了
Great.
我那是故意的 我在和体系作斗争
They were deliberate. I was fighting the system.
想在哪儿停就在哪儿停
Park anywhere, that's me.
好政策 我也经常这么做
Good policy. I do much the same.
对了 我是博士 如果有人感兴趣的话
I'm the Doctor by the way, if anyone's interested.
我是洛斯 大家好
And I'm Rose. Hello.
更好了 和我家的狗名字一样
Even better. That's the name of my dog.
尽管如此 至少我的端盘子员工在我这边
Still, at least I've got the catering staff on my side.
我就知道你不是叛徒
I knew you weren't a traitor.
为什么呢
Why's that, then?
我就是知道
I just did.
他们抓走了我的妻子
They took my wife.
她可能还活着
She might still be alive.
那就更糟了
That's even worse
因为卢密克所做的事
'cause that's what Lumic does.
他把活人抓走
He takes the living
然后把他们变成那些机器
and he turns them into those machines.
赛博人
Cybermen.
他们叫做赛博人
They're called Cybermen.
如果我是你 我会摘下这些耳机
And I'd take those Ear Pods off if I were you.
谁知道呢 也许卢密克在监听呢
You never know, Lumic could be listening.
他越界太远了 他再怎么说也只是个商人
But he's over-reached himself. He's still just a businessman.
他刺杀了总统
He's assassinated the President.
我们要做的就是通知有关部门
All we need to do is get to the city and inform the authorities.
因为我向你们保证 这事今晚到此为止
Because I promise you, this ends tonight.
我不朽的孩子
LUMIC: My everlasting children.
告诉我
Tell me,
你们感觉如何
how does it feel?
我们没有感觉
We feel nothing.
我是说你们脑袋里有何想法
But in your mind, what do you think?
我们想的一样 我们是统一的
We think the same. We are uniform.
但你们在想什么
But you think of what?
我们想到人类
We think of the humans.
想到他们的差异和痛苦
We think of their difference and their pain.
他们受着皮肉之苦
They suffer in the skin.
他们必须要升级
They must be upgraded.
好极了
Excellent.
我们开始吧
Then let's begin.
计算机 识别约翰·卢密克
Computer, identify John Lumic.
声纹识别确认有效
COMPUTER: Voice print acknowledged.
激活耳机主序列
Activate Ear Pod primary sequence.
请声明激活区域
Please state area of activation.
伦敦市
The city of London.
我刚刚宣布了伦敦的独立
I've just declared independence.
开始传送
Begin transmission.
他们都会到我这里来
LUMIC: They will come to me.
我的新孩子们
My new children.
不朽的人
The immortal ones.
整个伦敦都被封锁了
The whole of London has been sealed off.
报道说有一支军队
There are reports of an army,
金属人军队
an army of metal men.
所有公民请摘除你们的耳机
All citizens should remove their Ear Pods.
重复 摘除你们的耳机
I repeat, remove all Ear Pods.
伦敦已经全面戒严
London has been placed under martial law.
如果你听到了这条消息 请待在家里
If you are hearing this, stay in your homes.
重复 请待在家里
I repeat, stay in your homes.
噢 不是吧你
Oh, no, you don't!
怎么回事
MRS MOORE: What the hell?
发生什么事了
ROSE: What's going on?
是那些耳机 被卢密克控制着
It's the Ear Pods. Lumic's taken control.
我们何不…直接摘掉它们
Can't we just, I don't know, take them off?
不要
Don't.
这样会烧坏大脑的
It'll cause a brainstorm.
人类 作为一群智慧种族
The human race, for such an intelligent lot,
你们太容易受影响了
you aren't half susceptible.
如果真有机会把控制权交给一个人
Give anyone a chance to take control and you submit.
我觉得你们也许真会接受 轻松的活着
Sometimes I think you like it. Easy life.
嘿
Hey.
过来看看
Come and see.
他们要去哪儿
ROSE: Where are they all going?
我不知道
DOCTOR: I don't know.
卢密克一定有个作业基地
Lumic must have a base of operations.
巴特西
Battersea.
他就是在那里建造了他的原型机
That's where he was building his prototypes.
他为什么要这么做
Why's he doing it?
因为他快要死了
He's dying.
这一切的出发点就是为了延长寿命
This all started out as a way of prolonging life,
维持大脑存活
keeping the brain alive.
不惜任何代价
At any cost.
我好像见过这些赛博人 有没有
Thing is, I've seen Cybermen before, haven't I?
这种头盔 这种外形
The head, those handle shapes,
在范·斯塔邓的博物馆里
in Van Statten's Museum.
那是我们宇宙的赛博人
Oh, there are Cybermen in our universe.
他们起源于一个和这里一样普通的世界
They started on an ordinary world just like this,
然后成群地穿越星系
then swarmed across the galaxy.
这些是平行世界的版本
This lot are a parallel version.
这次他们从地球诞生
They're starting from scratch here on Earth.
你们在说什么
What the hell are you two on about?
别管这些了
Never mind.
快点 我们要离开这座城市
Come on, we need to get out of the city.
好的 分头行动
Okay, split up.
穆尔夫人 你照顾好他们
Mrs Moore, you look after that lot.
杰克 分散他们的注意 你走右 我走左
Jake, distract them, go right, I'll go left.
我们在桥街会合
We'll meet back at Bridge Street.
行动
Move.
我和他一起
I'm going with him.
快点 我们走
Come on. Let's go.
回来
DOCTOR: Back!
往哪儿走
Which way?
我不知道我们在哪
I don't know where we are.
他们发现我们了吗
Did they see us?
他们知道我们在哪儿吗
Do they know where we are?
我打赌他们看见了
I bet they saw us.
我打赌他们有追踪犬
I bet they send dog on us.
他们肯定有人造卫星
Bet they've got satellites.
他们在暗中看见我们了
They saw us in the dark.
他们知道我们在哪儿了
They know where we are.
我不明白 你是怎么回事
I don't get it. What is it with you?
你和我一模一样
You are exactly like me.
我不知道 我认为你比我勇敢
I don't know. I reckon you're braver.
没错 勇敢十倍
Oh, yeah. Ten times.
不过你的朋友也不赖 这我承认
Still, your friends aren't bad, I'll give you that.
那是博士和洛斯
Oh, that's the Doctor and Rose.
我只是追随他们的
I just tag along behind.
好 那你也不是太差
Well, then you're not that bad.
你真的这么想
Do you think?
差不多吧
Yeah, suppose.
赛博人
Cybermen.
分开走
Split up!
走
Go.
十二号改造间已关闭 准备消毒
TANNOY: Chamber 12 now closed for sterilisation.
所有抵抗者将被焚毁
All reject stock will be incinerated.
快点
Come on!
不要
No!
这个人不在项目内
CYBERMAN: This one is un-programmed.
奎恩先生 我一直把你看作可信任的人
Mr Crane, I thought you were one of the faithful.
噢 我确实是 先生
Oh, that I am, sir.
我的耳机一定出了故障
My Ear Pod must have malfunctioned,
对此我感到抱歉
for which I apologise.
我能否靠近点说话
If I might?
我很乐意请求升级 先生
I'd like to request an upgrade, sir.
我已经看到未来了
I've seen the future
是赛博斯企业的天下
and it's copyright Cybus Industries.
让我加入吧
Sign me up.
心甘情愿做志愿者
A willing volunteer?
你已经认识我很长时间了 先生
You've known me a long time, sir.
你我合作天衣无缝
Quite a team, you and me.
我一路追随你
I've been with you all the way.
但相信我 先生
But believe me, sir,
我太了解你了
knowing you so well,
我很清楚该怎么做
I know exactly what to do.
不
No!
不要 救命
No! Help me!
去死吧
Die, you...
救救我
Help me!
你很痛苦
You are in pain.
我们可以永久免除你的痛苦
We can remove pain forever.
不 现在不要
No. Not yet.
我还没准备好
I'm not ready.
我们会让你不朽
We will give you immortality.
我已经告诉过你
I've told you,
我会升级的
I will upgrade
但是只能在临终之时
only with my last breath.
现在就是时候了
Then breathe no more.
不不
No. No.
我命令你 不要
I command you. No!
我从河那边跑过来 你们应该看到了吧
I ran past the river, you should've seen it.
整个城市都布满军队
The whole city's on the march.
成百上千的赛博人 正沿着泰晤士河过来
Hundreds of Cybermen, all down the Thames.
他来了
Here he is.
你是哪一个
Which one are you?
对不起 那些赛博人 他没能…
I'm sorry, the Cybermen, he couldn't...
你是不是里奇
Are you Ricky?
米奇 是你吧 对不对
Mickey, that's you, isn't it?
是的
Yeah.
他努力了 他一直在跑
He tried. He was running.
他们数量太多了
There was too many of them.
别说了
Shut it.
我无能为力
There was nothing I could do.
别再说了
I said just shut it!
不准你再提起他
Don't even talk about him.
你什么都不是 你…
You're nothing, you are.
什么都不是
Nothing.
伦敦安全后我们再哀悼他
We can mourn him when London is safe.
现在 我们要向前看
For now, we move on.
整个伦敦都被封锁了
The whole of London's been sealed off
所有人口都被带到那个地方
and the entire population's been taken inside that place.
进行改造
To be converted.
我们要混进去把工厂关掉
We've got to get in there and shut it down.
我们要怎么做
How do we do that?
噢 我会想到办法的
Oh, I'll think of something.
你根本没有计划 只是走一步看一步
You're just making this up as you go along.
没错
Yep.
但我做得很机智
But I do it brilliantly.
这是老工厂的结构图
MRS MOORE: That's a schematic of the old factory.
看
Look,
冷却隧道就在车间下面
cooling tunnels underneath the plant
大小足够我们走过去
big enough to walk through.
我们从底下走 然后进入到控制中心
We go under then up into the control centre.
还有另一条路
There's another way in.
从前门进去
Through the front door.
如果他们带走了杰琪 她也会这样进去
If they've taken Jackie for upgrading, that's how she'll get in.
我们不能大摇大摆走进去
We can't just go strolling up.
噢 我们可以
Well, we could,
用这些
with these.
假耳机
Fake Ear Pods.
废了 没有信号
Dead, no signal.
但戴上它们 赛博人就误以为你是人群中的一个
But put them on, the Cybermen would mistake you for one of the crowd.
那就交给我吧
Then that's my job.
你不能表现出任何情感 一点都不行
You'd have to show no emotion, none at all.
有一点情感流露就会暴露身份
Any sign of emotion would give you away.
你有多少那玩意
How many of those have you got?
只有两副
just two sets.
好吧
Okay.
如果这是找到杰琪的最好方法
If that's the best way of finding Jackie,
那我和你一起去
then I'm coming with you.
她和你有什么关系
Why does she matter to you?
我们没时间了
We haven't got time.
博士 我和他一起 没有商量的余地
Doctor, I'm going with him and that's that.
什么都阻止不了你 对吧
No stopping you, is there?
是的
Nope.
跟你们说
Tell you what,
我们可以一次性攻击所有耳机
we can attack the Ear Pods at the same time.
让人们恢复神智
Give people their minds back
那他们就不会像梦游一样走进那地方
so they don't walk into that place like sheep.
杰克伙计
Jakey-boy.
卢密克在发送控制信号
Lumic's transmitting the control signal.
一定是从那里发出来的
It must be from over there.
就在那齐柏林飞艇上 看到没
There it is. On the zeppelin, do you see?
巨大的的传送器
Great big transmitter.
还好卢密克喜欢炫耀
Good thing Lumic likes showing off.
估计你能把这拿下吗
Reckon you can take it out?
没问题
Consider it done.
穆尔女士
Mrs Moore,
你能和我到冷却隧道里去吗
would you care to accompany me into the cooling tunnels?
我怎能拒绝冷却隧道呢
How could I refuse an offer of cooling tunnels?
我们兵分三路进攻 上面 正面 下面
We attack on three sides. Above, between, below.
进到控制中心 关掉转化器
We get to the control centre, we stop the conversion machines.
那我呢
What about me?
米奇
Mickey,
你可以…
you can, um...
怎样 远离麻烦 做一只铁皮狗
What? Stay out of trouble? Be the tin dog?
不 那些日子结束了
No, those days are over.
我要和杰克一路
I'm going with Jake.
我不需要你 笨蛋
JAKE: I don't need you, idiot.
我不是笨蛋
I'm not an idiot!
听到没有
You got that?
我能提供帮助
I'm offering to help.
随便吧
Whatever.
米奇
Mickey.
祝你好运
Good luck.
好的 你也是
Yeah. You, too.
洛斯 我们一会见
Rose, I'll see you later.
最好如此
Yeah, you'd better.
如果我们能活下来 我们在塔迪斯见
If we survive this, I'll see you back at the Tardis.
就这么说定了
That's a promise.
祝你好运
Good luck.
这里真冷
It's freezing.
有电灯开关吗
Any sign of a light switch?
什么都看不到
Can't see a thing.
但我有这个
But I've got these.
任何场合都用得上的装置
A device for every occasion.
戴上它
Put it on.
你包里有热狗吗 我饿死了
Haven't got a hot dog in there, have you? I'm starving.
那么多东西你偏偏想要这个
Of all the things to wish for.
那是机械复原肉
That's mechanically recovered meat.
我知道 这是食物中的赛博人 但是很好吃
I know. It's the Cyberman of food, but it's tasty.
拿把普通电筒也好
A proper torch as well.
看看我们到了什么地方
Let's see where we are.
已经改造好的 只是被冻结着
Already converted, just put on ice.
走吧
Come on.
我们走慢一点
DOCTOR: Let's go slowly.
当心别碰到启动机关
Keep an eye out for trip systems.
六号改造间现在开启升级人类
TAN NOY: Chamber 6 now open for human upgrading.
七号改造间现在开启升级人类
Chamber 7 now open for human upgrading.
八号改造间现在开启升级人类
Chamber 8 now open for human upgrading.
戴上它们 不要露出任何表情
just put them on. Don't show any emotion.
别露出迹象 什么都别有 行吗
No signs, nothing, okay?
别担心 我们能做到
Don't worry. We can do it.
我们可能会死在里面 你为什么要跟来
We could die in there. Why are you doing this?
这样说吧 我这么做是为了父母
Let's just say I'm doing it for my mum and dad.
好了 我们走
Right, let's go.
八号改造间现在开启升级人类
Chamber 8 now open for human upgrading.
九号改造间现在开启升级人类
Chamber 9 now open for human upgrading.
十号改造间现在开启升级人类
Chamber 10 now open for human upgrading.
十一号改造间现在开启升级人类
Chamber 11 now open for human upgrading.
两名守卫 我们可以拿下他们
Two guards. We can take them.
别杀他们
Don't kill them.
谁让你发号施令的
Who put you in charge?
如果你杀了他们 你和赛博人有什么区别
If you kill them, what's the difference between you and a Cyberman?
好吧 我们可以用这个
Well, I suppose we could use these.
嗅盐
Smelling salts?
比那个厉害一点
Bit stronger than that.
是穆尔夫人的一个小把戏
One of Mrs Moore's little tricks.
可以放倒他们
Should knock them out.
三、二、一
Three, two, one.
飞艇上警卫会更多
There's gotta be more guards on board.
我们进去解决他们
Then let's go get them.
你是怎么卷进来的
DOCTOR: How did you get into this, then?
怎么遇上传教士组织的
Rattling along with the Preachers?
我以前只是个普通人
MRS MOORE: Oh, I used to be ordinary.
在赛博斯企业工作
Worked at Cybus Industries,
朝九晚五
9-to-5.
直到有天我看到了不该看东西
Until one day, I find something I'm not supposed to.
主机里的一份文档
A file on the mainframe.
我只不过浏览了一下
All I did was read it.
然后 突然出现了一些持枪的男人
Then suddenly, I've got men with guns
半夜来敲我的门
knocking in the middle of the night.
我开始了逃亡
A life on the run.
后来我遇到了传教士
Then I found the Preachers.
他们需要一技术人员 所以我…
They needed a techie, so
就留了下来并慢慢适应了
I just sat down and taught myself everything.
穆尔先生呢
What about Mr Moore?
他不叫穆尔
Well, he's not called Moore.
这名字是从一本书上借来的
I got that from a book.
穆尔女士
Mrs Moore.
用假名比较安全
It's safer not to use real names.
但他以为我死了
But he thinks I'm dead.
这是保护他的唯一办法
It was the only way to keep him safe.
他和孩子们
Him and the kids.
那你呢
What about you?
有家庭吗
Got any family or...
谁需要家庭
Oh, who needs family?
我肩负着整个世界
I've got the whole world on my shoulders.
继续
Go on, then.
你的真名是什么
What's your real name?
安吉拉·普莱斯
Angela Price.
别告诉任何人
Don't tell a soul.
只字不提
Not a word.
六号冷库有动静
Movement in Deepcold 6.
唤醒军队
Awaken the army.
博士 那个好像动了
Doctor, did that one just move?
只是电筒的光而已
It's just the torchlight.
继续走 稳住
Keep going, come on.
他们醒了 快跑
They're waking up. Run!
上去
MRS MOORE: Get up!
快点
Quick!
他们过来了
They're coming!
打开 快打开
Open it! Open it!
上去
Get up!
快点 快点
Quick, quick!
安吉拉 快上来
Angela, come on!
配合得不错 穆尔女士
Oh, good team, Mrs Moore.
已有6500个单元完成改造
TANNOY: Units upgraded now 6,500.
重复 6500个单元 数目增加中
Repeat, 6,500 and rising.
你先等着
You will wait.
你还好吗
You Okay?
不好
No.
六号改造间现在开启升级人类
TANNOY: Chamber 6 now open for human upgrading.
所有抵抗者将被烧成灰烬
All reject stock will be incinerated.
看见杰琪了吗
Any Sign of Jackie?
你是皮特·泰勒
You are Peter Tyler.
确认 你是皮特·泰勒
Confirm. You are Peter Tyler.
是的
Confirm.
我识别出了你 我是第一个
I recognise you. I went first.
我的名字是杰奎琳·泰勒
My name was Jacqueline Tyler.
不
No.
什么
What?
他们不在项目内 阻止
They are un-programmed, restrain.
你说谎
You're lying,
你不是她 你不是我的杰琪
you're not her. You're not my Jackie.
现在我是赛博形态
Now I am Cyberform.
我曾经是杰奎琳·泰勒
Once l was Jacqueline Tyler.
但你不能
But you can't be.
你不是她…
Not her.
她的大脑在此躯体里
Her brain is inside this body.
杰琪 我是来救你的
Jacks, I came to save you.
这个人为赛博斯企业工作
This man worked with Cybus Industries
帮助创造了我们
to create our species.
他将得到强制奖励
He will be rewarded, by force.
把他们带到赛博控制中心
Take them to Cyber Control.
他们杀了她
They killed her.
他们把她带走并杀了她
They took her and killed her.
也许有这种可能 我不知道
Maybe there's a chance, I don't know.
也许我们可以逆转过程
Maybe we can reverse it.
我们无能为力
There's nothing we can do.
但是既然她有记忆…
But if she remembers...
她在哪儿
Where is she?
是哪一个 哪个是她
Which one was it? Which one was her?
他们全都一模一样
They all look the same.
好极了
Nice one,
没人守着 找找控制器在哪儿
nobody's home. Find the transmitter controls.
它长什么样子
What do they look like?
我哪知道
I don't know.
也许表面用红字写着"传送控制器"呢
They might have "transmitter controls" written in big red letters.
找找看
just look.
赛博人
Cyberman!
死的
It's dead.
我觉得它根本没有活过
I don't think it was ever alive.
空的 没有大脑
It's empty, no brain.
只是展示用的机器人外壳
It's just a robot suit. It's for display.
好吧
Okay.
找传送机
Transmitter.
你们没有升级
You are not upgraded.
是的
Yeah, well,
升级这个试试
upgrade this.
那是什么东西
What the hell was that thing?
电磁炸弹
Electromagnetic bomb.
它对计算机有效
Takes out computers.
我想也许能阻止赛博外壳
I figured it might stop a Cyber suit.
好 看来你是对的
Well, you figured right.
现在我们来看看这个
Now, let's have a look.
了解你的敌人
Know your enemy.
他们胸前还有商标
Got a logo on the front.
卢密克把他们做成品牌了
Lumic's turned them into a brand.
钢铁心脏
Heart of steel.
但你看
But look.
是肉吗
Is that flesh?
中枢神经系统
A central nervous system.
人工培育 缠绕在外壳里
Artificially grown then threaded throughout the suit
所以它能像活物一样作出反应
so it responds like a living thing.
对了 它就是活物
Well, it is a living thing.
噢 但看看
Oh, but look.
情感抑制装置
Emotional inhibitor.
切断他们的知觉
Stops them feeling anything.
但为什么呢
But Why?
这东西仍有人类大脑
It's still got a human brain.
想像一下 它看到自己会作何反应
Imagine its reaction if it could see itself.
意识到自己在这东西里面
Realise itself inside this thing.
它一定会发疯的
It would go insane.
所以他们切断了使人有人性的东西
So they cut out the one thing that makes them human.
他们必须这么做
Because they have to.
为什么…我…这么冷…
Why am I cold?
天哪 它活过来了
Oh, my God, it's alive.
它有感觉
It can feel.
我们打坏了情感抑制装置 很抱歉
We broke the inhibitor. I'm sorry.
真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
为什么这么冷
Why so cold?
你记得你的名字吗
Can you remember your name?
莎丽
Sally.
莎丽·费伦
Sally Phelan.
你是个女人
You're a woman.
盖瑞斯在哪儿
Where's Gareth?
谁是盖瑞斯
Who's Gareth?
他见不到我了
He can't see me.
在那不幸的夜晚之前
It's unlucky the night before.
你们要结婚了
You're getting married?
我好冷
I'm cold.
I'm so cold.
没事了
It's all right.
现在睡吧 莎丽
You sleep now, Sally.
好好睡吧
just go to sleep.
莎丽·费伦不会白白牺牲
Sally Phelan didn't die for nothing.
因为我们找到了关键
'Cause that's the key,
情感抑制装置
the emotional inhibitor.
如果我们能找出它的代码
If we could find the code behind it,
关闭代码
the cancellation code,
然后通过系统输入到每个赛博人的大脑里
then feed it throughout the system into every Cyberman‘s head,
他们就会意识到自己是什么
they'd realise what they are.
然后会发生什么
And what happens then?
我想那会让他们痛不欲生
I think it would kill them.
我们能这么做吗
Can we do that?
我们必须这么做
We've got to.
不然他们会杀死所有剩下的人
Before they kill everyone else.
我们别无选择 博士
There's no choice, Doctor.
必须这样做
It's got to be done.
不 你没必要杀她的
No! No! You didn't have to kill her!
传感器发现一个二进制导管系统
Sensors detect a binary vascular system.
你的升级信息不明
You are an unknown upgrade.
你要被带回去做分析
You will be taken for analysis.
传送控制器被封在这后面
The transmitter controls are sealed behind here.
我们需要高温焊枪之类的
We need oxyacetylene or something.
噢 我忘记把它带来了
Oh, and I forgot to bring it with me.
那我们怎么办
Then what do we do?
我们坠毁这艘飞艇
We'll crash the zeppelin.
我们还在里面
With us inside it?
我们把它设定自动然后溜走
We could set it on automatic and then just leg it.
来看看
Let's have a look.
锁住了
It's locked.
肯定有覆盖程序
There's got to be an override.
让我试试
Let me have a go.
我对计算机很在行 相信我
I'm good with computers. Trust me.
我被抓住了 但别担心
I've been captured but don't worry,
洛斯和皮特还在外面
Rose and Pete are still out there.
他们会救我的
They can rescue me.
算了吧
Oh, well, never mind.
你还好吗
You okay?
是的
Yeah.
他们抓了杰琪
But they got Jackie.
我们太晚了 卢密克杀了她
We were too late. Lumic killed her.
那么他人在哪
And where is he?
赫赫有名的卢密克先生
The famous Mr Lumic?
不给我们一个机会见见我们的上帝主人吗
Don't we get the chance to meet our lord and master?
他已经升级了
He has been upgraded.
那他和你一样了
So he's just like you?
他更优越
He is superior.
卢密克被设计为赛博管理员
The Lumic unit has been designated Cyber Controller.
钢铁时代来临了
This is the Age of Steel
而我就是创世主
and I am its creator.
快完成了
I'm almost there.
干得不错
Not bad work.
它动了
It's moving!
你说它是死的
You said it was dead!
外壳仍是完好的机器人
A robot suit's still a good robot.
等等
Wait a minute.
嘿 赛博人 来这里
Hey, Cyberman. Over here.
过来 你这没脑子的铁块
Come on, you brainless lump of metal.
过来试试
Come and have a go.
噢 不
WOMAN: Oh, no!
传送器搞定了
The transmitter is down!
那是我朋友的杰作 好样的
That's my friends at work. Good boys.
卢密克先生 我想那是自由意志的选票
Mr Lumic, I think that's a vote for free will.
我在七大洲都有工厂在待命
I have factories waiting on seven continents.
如果这些耳机失效了
If the Ear Pods have failed,
赛博人会强制征服人类
then the Cybermen will take humanity by force.
伦敦已经陷落了
London has fallen,
整个世界也会如此
so shall the world.
等等 我已经登陆到赛博控制器
Hold on, I've logged on to Cyber Control.
他们还活着
They're alive.
博士和洛斯 他们都在那里
The Doctor and Rose. There they are.
先不管他们 那玩意儿是什么
Never mind them, what the hell is that thing.
嘘 这东西有没有声音
Sh, if this thing got sound.
我会给整个世界带来和平
I will bring peace to the world.
永恒的和平
Everlasting peace
团结一致
and unity and uniformity.
那么想像力呢 你怎么看
And imagination? What about that?
正是想像力带领你走到今天
The one thing that led you here.
你现在要把它扼杀掉
Imagination, you're killing it dead.
你叫什么
What is your name.
我是博士
I'm the Doctor.
一个多余的头衔
A redundant title.
我们不再需要医生
Doctors need not exist.
赛博人永远不会生病
Cybermen never sicken.
但这就是重点
Yeah, but that's it.
这才是意义所在
That's exactly the point.
卢密克 你是个聪明人
Oh, Lumic, you're a clever man.
甚至可以称为天才 除了我在这
I'd call you a genius except I'm in the room.
你发明的一切 你和疾病斗争所作的一切
But everything you've invented, you did to fight your sickness,
太了不起了
and that's brilliant,
那非常符合人性
that is so human.
但一旦你摆脱了疾病和死亡
But once you get rid of sickness and mortality,
然后你还能为了什么而奋斗呢
then what's there to strive for, eh?
赛博人不会进步
The Cybermen won't advance.
你们只会停滞不前
You'll just stop.
你会永远保持这副模样
You'll stay like this forever.
金属世界 金属人 金属思想
A metal Earth with metal men and metal thoughts,
就是缺乏能使这星球充满生机的东西
lacking the one thing that makes this planet so alive.
人
People!
平凡的 愚蠢的 聪明的活人
Ordinary, stupid, brilliant people.
你为你的情感而自豪
You are proud of your emotions?
当然
Oh, yes.
那告诉我 博士
Then tell me, Doctor,
你是否经历过悲伤 愤怒 和痛苦
have you known grief and rage and pain?
是的 我经历过
Yes. Yes, I have.
是否令你心碎
And they hurt?
是的
Oh, yes.
我可以帮你摆脱
I can set you free.
你不想要吗
Would you not want that?
没有痛苦的生活
A life without pain?
你还不如杀了我
You might as well kill me.
那我恭敬不如从命
Then I take that option.
这不是你能索取的
It's not yours to take.
你是赛博管理员
You're a Cyber controller.
你不能控制我
You don't control me
以及任何有血有肉的事物
or anything with blood in its heart.
你没有办法阻止我
You have no means of stopping me.
我有军队
I have an army.
一个属于我的物种
A species of my own.
你还不明白 是吗
You just don't get it, do you?
一支军队又如何
An army's nothing.
那些普通人才是关键
There is all the ordinary people, they are the key
最平凡的人也能改变世界
The most ordinary people can change the world.
一些平凡的男人或女人
Some ordinary man or woman,
某个笨蛋
some idiot.
只需要他去寻找…
All it takes is for him to find,
比如一串正确的数字
say, the right numbers,
比如 正确的密码
say, the right code, say,
比如…情感抑制装置的代码
for example, the code behind the emotional inhibitor.
代码就在他面前
The code right in front of him.
如今即使是笨蛋也懂得电脑
‘Cause even an idiot knows his computers these days.
知道怎样通过防火墙和密码保护
Knows how to get past firewalls and passwords.
怎样解密卢密克家族数据库
Knows how to find something encrypted in the Lumic family database
只需要…皮特 什么二进制
under, what was it, Pete? Binary what?
九位二进制
Binary 9.
笨蛋都能找到那个代码
An idiot could find that code.
一条撤销代码
A cancellation code.
他不停的输入
And he'd keep on typing,
坚持战斗
keep on fighting,
坚持任何能挽救他朋友的东西
anything to save his friends.
你的话毫不相关
Your words are irrelevant.
是啊 说的太多了 那是我的毛病
Talk too much, that's my problem.
幸好我还有价格表 洛斯
Lucky I got you that cheap tariff, Rose,
我们所有聊天 通过你的电话
for all our long chats on your phone.
电话
The phone.
你会被删除
You will be deleted.
对 删除 控制 散列
Yes. Delete. Control. Hash.
那些可爱的按钮
All those lovely buttons.
然后 还有我个人最爱的
Then, of course, my particular favourite.
发送
Send.
让我们想想你当初是怎样诱惑那些平凡人的
And let's not forget how you seduced all those ordinary people in the first place,
使你的所有科技兼容所有其他系统
by making every bit of technology compatible with everything else.
是发给你的
It's for you.
比如这个
Like this.
太好了
Yes!
对不起
I'm sorry.
你做了什么
What have you done?
我让他们找回了灵魂
I gave them back their souls.
他们能看到你的所作所为 卢密克
They can see what you've done, Lumic,
这使他们痛不欲生
and it's killing them.
删除 删除
Delete! Delete!
删除
Delete!
没有出路
There's no way out.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我们必须逃出去
We've got to get away.
如果工厂爆炸会烧毁飞艇的
If that factory blows up, this balloon's gonna ignite.
开回去
Take it back!
米奇 他们没救了
Mickey, they've had it.
我说 开回去
I said take it back!
我们不能丢下他们
We're not leaving them behind.
绝对不能丢下他们
There's no way we're leaving them behind.
拿着
Hold it.
洛斯
Rose?
你能听见吗 快上屋顶
Rose, can you hear me? Head for the roof.
是米奇 他说上屋顶
It's Mickey. He says head for the roof.
不
No!
米奇 你从哪学会开这个东西的
Mickey, where did you learn to fly that thing?
游乐园 坚持住 洛斯
PlayStation Just hold on, Rose.
我来接你们了
I'm coming to get you.
你不能再下降了
You can't go any lower.
我必须下降
I've got to, man.
你会压扁他们的
You're gonna crush them.
肯定有什么办法的 肯定有
There's gotta be something, there's got to be.
噢 有了
Oh, yes.
你一定在开玩笑
You've got to be kidding.
洛斯 快上去
Rose, get on!
抓紧 我们要升空了
Hold on tight, we're going up.
米奇·史密斯航空公司欢迎你
Welcome to Mickey Smith Airlines.
祝你旅途愉快
Please enjoy your flight.
我们成功了 米奇成功了
We did it! Mickey did it!
皮特 拿着这个
Pete! Take this!
快用它
Use it!
按住按纽
Hold the button down.
然后对准绳子 照做
Press it against the rope. just do it!
杰琪·泰勒
Jackie Tyler.
这是为她报仇
This is for her.
那东西里面是什么情况
So what happens inside that thing, then?
你想进去看看吗
Do you want to see?
算了吧
I don't think so.
但是你们两个 你们说的那些事
But you two, you know, all that stuff you said
什么另一个世界的事
about different worlds.
你到底是谁
Who are you?
就像你说的
It's like you said.
想像一下有个不同的世界
Imagine there are different worlds.
平行世界
Parallel worlds.
在那里有另一个皮特·泰勒
Worlds with another Pete Tyler
杰琪·泰勒仍然活着
and Jackie Tyler is still alive.
还有他们的女儿
And their daughter.
我得走了
I've got to go.
但如果你愿意看看里面…
But if you just look inside...
我不能
I can't.
到处都是卢密克的工厂
There's all those Lumic factories out there,
还储藏着很多赛博人
all those Cybermen still in storage.
总要有人告诉当局究竟发生了什么
Someone's got to tell the authorities what happened.
继续战斗
Carry on the fight.
洛斯
Rose.
我只有五分钟的能源
I've only got five minutes of power.
我们得走了
We've got to go.
博士可以教你
The Doctor could show you how.
谢谢你…所做的一切
Thank you for everything.
爸爸
Dad...
不要
Don't.
别这样
just don't.
在这里
MICKEY: Here it is.
我找到了
I found it.
一点都没皱
Not a crease.
我的外套
My suit.
好家伙
Good man.
好了 杰克 我们要走了
Now then, Jake, we've got to run,
还有一件事
but one more thing.
穆尔女士 她的真名是安吉拉·普莱斯
Mrs Moore, her real name was Angela Price.
她还有丈夫和孩子
She's got a husband out there and children.
找到他们
Find them.
告诉他们她如何拯救世界而牺牲
Tell them how she died saving the world.
好的 我一定会的
Yeah, course I will.
那我们走了
Off we go, then.
呃
Erm...
有一件事 我要留下
Thing is, I'm staying.
你要干什么
You're doing what?
但是你不能
You can't.
算是保持平衡吧
It sort of balances out
这个世界失去了里奇
'cause this world lost its Ricky,
但还有我
but there's me.
而且有很多事要做
And there's work to be done
还有很多赛博人需要处理
with all those Cybermen still out there.
但你不能留下
But you can't stay.
洛斯 我奶奶在这里
Rose, my gran's here.
她还活着 我年迈的奶奶 记得她吗
She's still alive. My old gran, remember her?
记得
Yeah.
她需要我
She needs me.
那我呢 如果我需要你呢
What about me? What if I need you?
是的 但洛斯 你不需要我
Yeah, but Rose, you don't.
只需要你和他 不是吗
It's just you and him, isn't it?
我们很久以前有过牵绊 但…
We had something a long time ago,
现在不再有了
but not anymore.
我们还会回来的
Well, we'll come back.
我们能去到任何地方 过来看你 好吗
We can travel anywhere. Come and see you, yeah?
我们不能了
We can't.
我告诉过你 穿越平行世界是不可能的
I told you, travel between parallel worlds is impossible.
我们到这里只是意外
We only got here by accident.
我们掉进了时空裂缝
We fell through a crack in time.
当我们离开时 我得把裂缝补好
When we leave, I've got to close it.
我们永远不能回来了
We can't ever return.
博士
Doctor.
拿着洛斯的手机
Take Rose's phone.
代码在里面
It's got the code.
把它带到那里去
Get it out there.
阻止那些工厂
Stop those factories.
祝你好运
Good luck.
笨蛋米奇
Mickey the idiot.
注意点
Watch it.
谢谢
Thanks.
我们有过一段美好时光 对不对
We've had a laugh, though, haven't we?
经历了这一切 回头想想
Seen it all, been there and back.
谁能想到你和我会摆脱旧生活
Who'd have thought, me and you, off that old estate,
在星球之间穿行
flying through the stars.
过去我们只是坐在那里
All those years, just sitting there...
想像某天我们会做什么
imagining what we'd do one day.
我们根本没有预料到这个 不是吗
We never saw this, did we?
快走 别耽误你们航程
Go on. Don't miss your flight.
杰克 看看这个 你会喜欢的
Jake, you want to watch this.
什么情况
JAKE: What the hell?
那就是博士
MICKEY: That's the Doctor
乘着塔迪斯
in the Tardis.
和洛斯·泰勒一起
With Rose Tyler.
你还活着
You're alive.
妈妈 你还活着
Oh, Mum, you're alive.
当然了 我还是和以前一个样
Well, I was the last time I looked.
怎么了 发生什么事了 宝贝
What is it? What's happened, sweetheart?
发生什么了 你们去哪儿了
What's wrong? Where did you go?
很远的地方
Far away.
那是…遥不可及的远方
That was far away.
米奇去哪了
Where's Mickey?
他回家了
He's gone home.
我知道这一时难以接受 我长的里奇一样
I know it's not easy with my face looking exactly like Ricky,
但我和他不一样 我不是来取代他的
but I'm a different man, I'm not replacing him.
但我们可以永远铭记他
But we can remember him
以他的名义继续斗争
by fighting in his name.
所有那些的赛博工厂
With all those cyber factories out there,
你觉得巴黎也有一间么
do you think there'd be one in Paris?
是的
Yeah.
那我们去解放巴黎吧
Then let's go and liberate Paris.
什么 就你和我
What, you and me?
用一辆货车
In a van?
货车没什么问题
There's nothing wrong with a van.
我曾用一辆黄色的卡车拯救了宇宙呢
I once saved the universe with a big yellow truck.
出发了 先生
There you go, sir.
准备迎接重大时刻
All wired up for the great occasion.
谁来救救我
WOMAN: Someone help me, please!
这事在这个地方到处发生着
It's happening all over the place.
他们正在变成怪物
They're turning into monsters.
普通人被击中后改变了
ROSE: Ordinary people are being struck down and changed
房间里唯一的新事物是电视机
and the only new thing in the house is a television.
黑衣人
Men in black?
消失的警车
Vanishing police cars?
这是丘吉尔的英国 不是斯大林的苏联
This is Churchill's England, not Stalin's Russia.
你坐好了吗
Are you sitting comfortably?
好的
Good.
那我们开始吧
Then we'll begin.